Guide to the Cannon Mills Records, 1836-1983 RL.00187
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Barringer Manufacturing Company Series, 1907-1928
  Charter and bylaws, minute books, gold bonds, stock ledgers, stock certificate books, and scattered correspondence, financial statements, stock holder proxies, and historical and biographical information. James W. Cannon and the Rev. Paul Barringer, each a one- third owner, established the mill in 1907. It became Cannon Mills Plant No. 11 in 1928. In 1927 the factory had 13,964 spindles that produced yarn, beams, balls, tubes, and skeins. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Boxed Files and Volumes
    - Information Folder (Box 166)
    - Bylaws, 1919 (Box 166)
    - Charter, 1907 (Box 166)
    - Charter Amended, 1912 (Box 166)
    - Correspondence, 1909-1928 and undated Financial Statements, 1918-1927 (Box 166)
    - Gold Bonds, 1911-1912: (Box 167)
      - Nos. 1-60, 3 folders (Box 167)
    - Minutes of Meetings of Stockholders and Directors, 1919-1928 (Box 167)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1907-1918 (Box 167)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1918-1928 (Box 167)
    - Miscellaneous Legal and Financial Papers, 1920 and undated (Box 168)
    - Stock Certificate Book, No. 1-132, 1909-1926 (Box 168)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 132-260, 1920-1928 (Box 168)
    - Stock Ledger, 1907-1910 (bulk, 1907-1909) (Box 169)
    - Stock Ledger, 1909-1928 (Box 169)
    - Stockholder List, 1919 (Box 169)
    - Stockholder Proxies, 1926, July (Box 169)
    - Stockholder Proxies, 1927, July (Box 169)
- L. T. Barringer and Co. Series, 1932-1983
  Minutes of the meetings of the stockholders and directors and scattered correspondence and financial statements of a major cotton brokerage house at Memphis, Tennessee, doing both domestic and foreign business. Lewis T. Barringer of the North Carolina Barringer family founded the firm. It merged into Cannon Mills in 1983. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Boxed Files and Volumes
    - Information Folder (Box 169)
    - Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 169)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1953, Including Minutes of Some Directors' Meetings (Box 169)
    - Financial Statements, 1932-1933 (Box 169)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1933-1955 (Box 169)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1956-1972 (Box 170)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1973-1979 (Box 170)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1979-1983 (Box 170)
- Bloomfield Manufacturing Company Series, 1919-1930
  Ledgers, invoice book, and miscellaneous financial records of this cotton mill at Statesville, N.C., established in 1903 and owned by Cannon Mills during ca. 1928-1935. In 1930 the mill had 6,944 spindles and produced combed peeler, ball warps, and cones. Files arranged alphabetically and volumes shelved numerically.
  - Boxed Files
    - Information Series (Box 171)
    - Taxes:
      - North Carolina, 1919-1921 (Box 171)
    - Trial Balance, 1920 (Box 171)
    - Yarn Sales, 1928, Jan.-1930, Nov., 6 folders (Box 171)
  - Volumes Shelved in Numerical Sequence
    - Ledger, 1919-1922 (Volume 92)
    - Ledger, 1922-1926 (Volume 93)
    - Invoice and Record Book No. 1, 1928-1930 (Volume 94)
- Brown Manufacturing Company Series, 1949-1963
  Stock records of this textile mill at Concord, N.C., founded in 1905, operated for many years by the Johnston family, and owned by Cannon Mills from 1956 until closure in ca. 1970-1971. The factory had 15,216 spindles producing outings, shirtings, and interlinings in 1953. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Boxed Files and Volumes
    - Preferred Stock Certificate No. 200 (Box OV1)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 601-799, 1949-1963 (Box OV1)
    - Stock Purchases, March, 1956, 2 folders (Box OV1)
- Brown-Roberta Foundation Series, 1947-1960
  Chiefly bank records of this organization at Concord, N.C., that contributed funds, usually less than $500, to schools, social groups, health organizations, charities, and especially to churches. Related to the Johnston textile interests until the Cannons assumed control in the 1950s. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Boxed Files and Volumes
    - Information Folder (Box 171)
    - Bank Statements and Cancelled Checks, 1953-1960, 2 folders (Box 171)
    - Checkbook, 1947-1959 (Box 171)
    - Correspondence, Aug, 1959 (Box 171)
    - Minutes, Feb. 15, 1960 (Box 171)
- Roberta Manufacturing Company Series, 1910-1978
  Stock certificate book and minute books of the stockholders and directors of this hosiery yearn manufacturer in Cabarrus County. The Cannons acquired control from the Johnston family in 1956 and operated the mill until its liquidation in 1978. Never a large mill, Roberta had 6,054 spindles in both 1929 and 1950. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Boxed Volumes
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1932-1972, Including Certificate of Incorporation and By-Laws and Directors' Minutes, 1910 (Box 172)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1973-1978 (Box 172)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 1-52, 1915-1963 (Box 172)
- Cabarrus Cotton Mills Series, 1893-1928
  Extensive but incomplete account books including stock records, ledgers, journals, trial balances, financial statements, bank ledgers, cash records, notes payable and receivable, and miscellaneous volumes and files concerning the charter, employees, and finances. The Cannons were among the founders of the company. There were plants at Kannapolis and Concord that became Cannon Mills' Plants No. 4 and No. 5 respectively in 1928. The Concord factory produced sheeting with 28,016 spindles in 1927, and the facility at Kannapolis had 80,000 spindles making combed yarns, sheetings, and fabrics. Files arranged alphabetically and volumes shelved numerically.
  - Boxed Files and Volumes
    - Bankruptcy Forms, 1922 (Box 173)
    - Census of Manufactures, 1919 (Box 173)
    - Charter:
      - Documents Relating to Its Adoption and Amendment, 1893-1922 (Box 173)
    - Correspondence, 1928 (Box 173)
    - Cotton Purchase Invoices, 1906-1907 (Box 173)
    - Depreciation, 1926 (Box 173)
    - Draper Company, Hopedale, Massachusetts:
      - Specifications for Loom and Parts, 1902 (Box 173)
    - Financial Statement, 1921, July 1 (Box 173)
    - History, 1893 (Box 173)
    - Mill House Insurance, ca. 1915 (Box 173)
    - Mill Houses Rent, 1924-1926 (Box 173)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1893-1908, Including Stock Ledger, 1893-1905 (Box 173)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1893-1908:
      - Stock Transfers, Stockholder Lists, and Memoranda, 1893-1907 and undated, Found Inside the Volume (Box 173)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1909-1918 (Box 173)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1919-1928 (Box 174)
    - Notes Payable and Receivable, 1902-1928 (Volume also contains Imperial Cotton Mills Notes Payable and Receivable, 1909-1928) (Box 174)
    - Payroll:
      - Unclaimed Wages, 1924, Aug.-1929, Feb., 5 folders (Box 174)
    - Payroll Book, July, 1914-Jan., 1922 (Box 175)
    - Payroll Book, Jan., 1922-Aug., 1924 (Box 175)
    - Preferred Stock Certificate Books (See below) (Box 175)
    - Preferred Stock Ledger, 1919-1923 (Box 175)
    - Southern Railway Company, 1901 (Box 175)
    - Stock Certificate Books (See below) (Box 175)
    - Stock Ledger, 1908-1914 (Box 175)
    - Stock Ledger, 1914-1922 (Box 175)
    - Stock Purchases, 1906 (Box 175)
    - Stockholders, 1908-1909, 1919-1924 (Box 175)
    - Taxes:
      - State and Local, 1921 (Box 175)
    - Time Book, Night Carding and Spinning, 1897, Sept.- 1989, Oct. (Box 175)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 261-496, 1906-1914 (Box 176)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 497-743, 1914-1918 (Box 176)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 744-1003, 1919-1920 (Box 177)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 1004-1245, 1920-1922 (Box 177)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 1246-1499, 1922-1927 (Box 178)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 1501-1525, 1927-1928 (Box 178)
    - Preferred Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 1-250, 1919-1920 (Box 179)
    - Preferred Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 251-445, 1920-1921 (Box 180)
    - Preferred Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 446-689, 1921-1925 (Box 181)
    - Preferred Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 690-741, 1926-1928 (Box 182)
  - Volumes Shelved in Numerical Sequence
    - Stock Ledger, 1908-1914 (Box 175)
    - Stock Ledger, 1914-1922 (Box 175)
    - Stock Ledger, 1922-1928 (Volume 95)
    - Preferred Stock Ledger, 1919-1923 (Box 175)
    - Preferred Stock Ledger, 1923-1928 (Volume 96)
    - Ledger No. 2, 1902-1909 (Volume 97)
    - Current Ledger No. 3, 1910-1920 (Volume 98)
    - Transfer Ledger No. 3, 1910-1920 (Volume 99)
    - General Ledger No. 1, 1926-1928 (Volume 100)
    - Journal No. 1, 1893, Jan.-1897, July (Volume 101)
    - Journal No. 2, 1897, Aug.1901, April (Volume 102)
    - Journal No. 3, 1901, Feb.-1903, Sept. [bulk, 1901, April, 1903, Sept., Sept.] (Volume 103)
    - Journal No. 4, 1903, Oct.-1912, March (Volume 104)
    - Journal, 1914, July-1922, Aug. (Volume 105)
    - Journal, 1922, Sept.-1925, Aug. (Volume 106)
    - Journal, 1925, Sept.-1926, June (Volume 107)
    - Journal No. 1, 1926, July-1928, July (Volume 108)
    - Trial Balance Book, 1918, April-1927, June (Volume also includes Imperial Cotton Mills, Trial Balances, 1918, April-1927, Dec. (Volume 109)
    - Trial Balance Book, 1927, July-1928, July (Volume 110)
    - Trial Balance Book for Income and Expense Accounts at Kannapolis and Concord Plants, 1927. Jan.-1928, May (Volume 111)
    - Financial Statements and Inventories, 1894-1919 (Volume 112)
    - Bank Ledger No. 2, 1904, April-1909, June (Volume 113)
    - Bank Ledger No. 3, 1909, July-1914, July (Volume 114)
    - Bank Ledger No. 4, 1914, Aug.-1918, Aug. (Volume 115)
    - Bank Ledger No. 5, 1918, Sept.-1921, Feb. (Volume 116)
    - Bank Ledger No. 6, 1921, March-1923, June (Volume 117)
    - Bank Ledger No. 7, 1923, June-1925, June (Volume 118)
    - Bank Ledger No. 8, 1925, July-Aug. (Volume 119)
    - Bank Ledger No. 1, 1926, Sept.-1928, July (Volume 120)
    - Cashbook No. 2, 1903, July-1909, Dec. (Volume 121)
    - Cashbook No. 3, 1901, Jan.-1914, June (Volume 122)
    - Cashbook No. 1, 1914, July-1918, Nov. (Volume 123)
    - Cashbook No. 2, 1918, Dec.-1922, Aug. (Volume 124)
    - Cashbook No. 3, 1922, Sept.-1925, Aug. (Volume 125)
    - Cash Receipts Journal, 1925, Sept.-1926, June (Volume 126)
    - Cash Receipts Book, 1926, July 2-1928, July 7 (Volume 127)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal, 1925, Sept.-1926, June (Volume 128)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal, 1926, July-1927, Dec. (Volume 129)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 1, 1928, Jan.-Aug. (Volume 130)
    - Notes Payable and Receivable, 1902-1928 (Volume also includes Imperial Cotton Mills, Notes Payable and Receivable, 1909-1928) (Box 174)
    - Cotton Purchases Register, 1926, April-1927, June (Volume 131)
    - Depreciation Schedule, 1909-1927 (Volume 132)
    - Shipping Book, 1923 (Volume 133)
- Franklin Cotton Mills Series, 1908-1928
  Minute books of stockholders and directors and considerable financial information and scattered records for payroll, production, sales, tenants, consolidation with Cannon Mills, and construction. The account books are ledgers, journals, and cashbooks. James W. Cannon and his sons founded the mill in 1906. The factory, operator of 25,500 spindles in 1927 producing warp yarns, became Cannon Mills' Plant No. 9 in 1928. Files arranged alphabetically and volumes shelved numerically.
  - Boxed Files and Volumes
    - Appraisal, 1926 (Box 183)
    - Audit Reports, 1921, 1923 (Box 183)
    - Bankruptcy Forms, 1922 (Box 183)
    - Census of Manufactures, 1925 (Box 183)
    - Construction by T. C. Thompson & Bros., 1913 (Box 183)
    - Correspondence, 1918-1922 (Box 183)
    - Cotton Purchases, 1906, 1915, July-1916, Dec., 5 folders (Box 183)
    - Deeds, 1928 (Box 183)
  - Boxed Files and Volumes
    - Financial Statements, 1906, 1917-1920, 1922-1926, 4 folders (Box 184)
    - General File, 1926-1927 (Box 184)
    - Journal Entries and Supporting Papers, 1925-1927, 2 folders (Box 184)
    - Mill House Tenant Evictions, 1921 (Box 184)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1918-1919, Including Additional Financial Statements, 1920-1926 (Box 184)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1919-1928 (Box 185)
    - Payroll, 1919 (Box 185)
    - Promissory Notes and Cancelled Checks, 1920-1926 (Box 185)
    - Purchase by Cannon Manufacturing Company, 1926-1927 (Box 185)
    - Sales Invoices, 1927 (Box 185)
    - Stock Certificate Book, 1918-1928 (Box 185)
    - Superintendent's Reports, 1922-1925 (Box 185)
    - Taxes: (Box 186)
      - Federal, 1919-1926 (Box 186)
    - Taxes:
      - Local, 1920-1925 (Box 186)
    - Taxes:
      - North Carolina, 1919-1927 (Box 186)
    - Taxes:
      - State and Local, 1920-1921 (Box 186)
    - Trial Balances, 1918-1926 and undated, 3 oversize folders (Box 239)
    - Westford Methodist Church, 1925 (Box 186)
    - Yarn Production and Sales, 1919-1920 (Box 186)
  - Volumes Shelved in Numerical Sequence
    - Ledger No. 1, 1906-1908 (Volume 134)
    - Transfer Ledger, 1908-1920 (Volume 135)
    - Ledger No. 2, 1910-1918 (Volume 136)
    - Ledger, 1918-1925 (bulk 1918-1924) (Volume 137)
    - Ledger, 1927-1928 (Volume 138)
    - Loose-Leaf Ledger, 1927-1928 (Volume 139)
    - Journal, 1906-1908 (Volume 140)
    - Journal, 1908-1922 (Volume 141)
    - Journal, 1910-1918 (Selected entries only) (Volume 142)
    - Journal, 1922-1928 (Volume 143)
    - Journal, 1928, April-July (Volume 144)
    - Trial Balance Book, 1918, April-1919, May (Volume 145)
    - Cashbook, 1906, Sept.-1908, Dec. (Volume 146)
    - Cashbook, 1908, Oct.-1917, Nov. (Volume 147)
    - Cashbook, 1917, Dec.-1925, Jan. (Volume 148)
    - Cashbook, 1925, Jan.-1928, July (Volume 149)
- Gibson Manufacturing Company Series, 1899-1928
  Chiefly minute books of the stockholders and directors, stock certificate books, and stock ledger of this mill founded at Concord, N.C., in 1899. The Cannons and the Southern Power Company were early minority stockholders. The factory became Cannon Mills' Plant No. 6 in 1928. Gibson had 31,396 spindles in 1927 that manufactured colored yarns, fancy ginghams, dress goods, etc. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Boxed Files and Volumes
    - Cotton Purchase Invoices, 1906-1907 (Box 186)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1899-1908, Including Register of Stock Certificates, 1900-1904 (Box 186)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1908-1920 (Box 186)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1920-1928 (Box 186)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 1-250, 1900-1902 (Box 187)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 251-497, 1902-1906 (Box 187)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 498-748, 1906-1914 (Box 188)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 749-1000, 1915-1922 (Box 188)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 1001-1250, 1922 (Box 189)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 1251-1409, 1922-1928 (Box 189)
    - Preferred Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 1-200, 1904-1917 (Box 190)
    - Preferred Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 201-229, 1917-1928 (Box 191)
    - Stock Ledger, 1900-1928 (Box 192)
    - Stockholder Lists, 1919 (Box 192)
    - Taxes:
      - State and Local, 1920-1921 (Box 192)
- Hobarton Manufacturing Company Series, 1923-1928
  Minutes of meetings of stockholders and directors and stock records of this textile mill established at Concord, N.C., in 1923 by Charles A. Cannon and others. In 1925 the factory had 112 narrow looms, employed 100 persons and produced fine ginghams and fancy dress goods. Hobarton was consolidated in 1928 with Gibson Manufacturing Company to become Cannon Mills' Plant No. 6. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Boxed Volumes
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1923-1928 (Box 192)
    - Stock Certificate Book, 1923-1924 (Box 193)
    - Stock Certificate Book, 1924-1928 (Box 193)
    - Stock Ledger, 1923-1928 (Box 193)
- Imperial Cotton Mills Series, 1909-1976
  Extensive, but incomplete, account books including ledgers; journals; trial balances; balances of income, expense, and accounts receivable accounts; bank ledgers; and cash records. Several files contain minutes and legal, financial, and stockholder information. Imperial, established by James W. Cannon in 1909 at Eatonton, Georgia, was not part of the consolidation in 1928 and continued as an affiliate of Cannon Mills until closure in 1976. The factory had 16,208 spindles producing sheetings in 1971. Files arranged alphabetically and volumes shelved numerically.
  - Boxed Files and Volumes
    - Information Folder (Box 194)
    - Appraisal, 1926 (Box 194)
    - Bankruptcy Forms, 1922 (Box 194)
    - By-Laws, 1909 (Box 194)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1957-1976 (Box 194)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Directors, 1918, 1926-1927 (Box 194)
    - Petition to Incorporate, 1909 (Box 194)
    - Stockholder List, 1919 or 1920 (Box 194)
  - Volumes Shelved in Numerical Sequence
    - Current Ledger No. 1, 1909-1920 (Volume 150)
    - Transfer Ledger No. 1, 1909-1919 (Volume 151)
    - General Ledger, 1970-1971 (Volume 152)
    - General Journal, 1909, July-1921, June (Volume 153)
    - General Journal, 1921, July-1934, Dec. (Volume 154)
    - General Journal, 1935, Jan.-1941, Nov. (Volume 155)
    - General Journal, 1941, Dec.-1945, Nov. (Volume 156)
    - General Journal, 1945, Dec.-1954, Jan. (Volume 157)
    - General Journal, 1954, Feb.-1962, June (Volume 158)
    - General Journal, 1962, July-1970, Oct. (Volume 159)
    - Trial Balance Book, 1918, April-1927, Dec. (In volume with Cabarrus Cotton Mills, Trial Balance Book, 1918, April-1927, June) (Volume 109)
    - Trial Balance Book, 1928, Jan.-1960, Nov. (Volume 160)
    - Balances of Income, Manufacturing Expense, Administrative and General Expense, and Accounts Receivable Accounts, 1929, Jan.-1947, Nov. (Volume 161)
    - Balances of Income, Manufacturing Expense, Administrative and General Expense, and Accounts Receivable Accounts, 1947, Dec.-1960, Nov. (Volume 162)
    - Bank Ledger No. 1, 1909, May-1916, May (Volume 163)
    - Bank Ledger No. 2, 1916, June-1920, Oct. (Volume 164)
    - Bank Ledger No. 3, 1920, Oct.-1924, Jan. (Volume 165)
    - Bank Ledger No. 4, 1924, Feb.-1926, July (Volume 166)
    - Bank Ledger No. 5, 1926, July-1932, Feb. (Includes Social Circle Cotton Mills' Bank Ledger, 1931-1932) (Volume 167)
    - Bank Ledger No. 1, 1932, March-1944, May (Volume 168)
    - Bank Ledger No. 2, 1944, June -1957, April (Volume 169)
    - Bank Ledger No. 5, 1966, July -1971, May (Volume 170)
    - Cashbook No. 1, 1909, May-1916, Feb. (Volume 171)
    - Cashbook No. 2, 1916, Feb.-1920, April (Volume 172)
    - Cashbook No. 3, 1920, April-1923, June (Volume 173)
    - Cashbook No. 4, 1923, July-1927, June (Volume 174)
    - Cash Receipts Journal No. 1, 1927, July-1952, Sept. (Volume 175)
    - Cash Receipts Journal No. 2, 1952. Oct.-1958, Dec. (Volume 176)
    - Cash Receipts Journal No. 3, 1959, Jan.-1964, Nov. (Volume 177)
    - Cash Receipts Journal No. 4, 1964, Dec.-1971, Jan. (Volume 178)
    - Cash Receipts Journal No. 5, 1971, Feb.-April (Volume 179)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 1, 1927, July-1930, July (Volume 180)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 2, 1930, Aug-1934, Nov. (Volume 181)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 3, 1934, Dec.-1938, Nov. (Volume 182)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 4, 1938, Dec.-1942, Sept. (Volume 183)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 5, 1942, Oct.-1946, June (Volume 184)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 6, 1946, July-1950, Jan. (Volume 185)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 7, 1950, Feb.-1953, Aug. (Volume 186)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 8, 1953, Sept.-1956, Dec. (Volume 187)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 9, 1957, Jan.-1960, June (Volume 188)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 10, 1960, July-1963, Nov. (Volume 189)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 11, 1963, Dec.-1967, Nov. (Volume 190)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 12, 1967, Dec.-1971, April (Volume 191)
    - Notes Payable and Receivable, 1909-1928 (Included in Cabarrus Cotton Mills, Notes Payable and Receivable, 1902-1928) (Box 174)
- J. A. Skipwith and Co. Series, 1908-1912
  Order ledger and journal (including invoice register for yarn) for this firm of cotton brokers at Concord, N.C. Skipwith served as buying and receiving agent for Cabarrus Cotton Mills, Patterson Manufacturing Co., Cannon Manufacturing Co., Kesler Manufacturing Co., Wiscassett Mills, Gibson Manufacturing Co., Tuscarora Cotton Mill, Durham Hosiery Mill, Franklin Cotton Mill, Imperial Cotton Mill, Buck Creek Cotton Mills, and Amazon Cotton Mills. Volumes shelved numerically.
  - Volumes Shelved in Numerical Sequence
    - Journal, 1907, Oct.-1911, Aug. (Including Invoice Register for Yarn, 1916, Jan.- 1919, Aug. possibly for another company) (Volume 192)
    - Order Ledger, 1908, Sept.-1912, Sept. (Volume 193)
- Kesler Manufacturing Company Series, 1895-1928
  Stockholder records, charter and bylaws, minutes, scattered correspondence and financial papers of this textile mill founded at Salisbury, N.C., in 1895. Rare and unusual access to the operations of a textile factory is provided by the diary of Superintendent John C. Mason who managed Kesler. The Cannons and the Rev. Francis Johnstone Murdoch became stockholders and executives. In 1925 the mill had 27,456 spindles and produced sheetings. During the consolidation of 1928 Kesler became Cannon Mills' Plant No. 7. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Boxed Files and Volumes
    - Annual Reports, 1919-1927 (Box 195)
    - By-Laws, 1918 and undated (Box 195)
    - Cannon, Charles A., 1921-1925 (Box 195)
    - Cannon, James W., 1918 (Box 195)
    - Cannon Mills, New York City, Selling Agent, 1918 (Box 195)
    - Charter, 1895 (Box 195)
    - Charter Amended, 1922 (Box 195)
    - Correspondence, 1920-1927 (Box 195)
    - Cotton Purchase Invoices, 1906 (Box 195)
    - Diary, Jan. 1, 1908-April 1, 1911, of John C. Mason, Superintendent (82 p.) (Box 195)
    - Diary,, 1908, Jan. 1-1911, April 1, of John C. Mason, Superintendent: Notes about and Extracts from the Diary (Box 195)
    - Diary, 1908, Jan. 1-1911, April 1, of John C. Mason, Superintendent: Specifications, Calculations, and Billheads with Vignette of Mill Found within Diary (Box 195)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1895-1916 (Box 195)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1916-1928 (Box 196)
    - Minutes and Papers Related to Meetings of Stockholders and Directors, 1922-1928, undated (Box 196)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 1-600, 1896-1921 (Box 197)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 601-666, 1921-1922 (Box 198)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 667-857, 1922-1928 (Box 199)
    - Stock Subscribers, 1895 and 1919 (Box 199)
    - Stockholder Proxies, 1921 (Box 199)
    - Taxes:
      - Income, 1915 (Box 199)
  - Volume Shelved in Numerical Sequence
    - Stock Ledger, 1896-1928 (Volume 194)
- Klumac Cotton Mills Series, 1922-1936, bulk 1934-1935
  Customer files, lawsuits, correspondence, financial statements, sales invoices, and weekly production and sales reports of this factory at Salisbury, N.C., that produced damask and rayon bedspreads. Klumac sold its goods through Cannon Mills in New York City, and Cannon also assisted with finishing work in North Carolina. Klumac had economic difficulties in the mid-1930s, went into receivership, and did not operate for several years. Cannon sued Klumac in 1934. The records document the Cannon-Klumac relationship and its difficulties. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Boxed Files
    - Butler Bros., 1934 (Box 200)
    - Cannon Mills vs. Klumac Cotton Mills, 1929-1936 (Box 200)
    - Correspondence: